<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Blood Bowl Companion</string>
    <string name="app_info">App Info</string>
    <string name="app_home">Home</string>
    <string name="current_version">Version:  1.0.0</string>


    <string name="app_info_text_title">About the Blood Bowl Companion App</string>
    <string name="app_info_description">I made this app to be a quick reference for Blood Bowl players during their game.
    It is to be used alongside the official handbook for when you need to quickly check a table or skill.</string>
    <string name="app_info_disclaimer">This is an unofficial application that is not endorsed in any way by Games Workshop Limited or any of
    its subsidiaries. Blood Bowl is a trademark of Games Workshop Limited. All Rights Reserved to their respective owners.</string>

    <string-array name="list_headers">
        <item>Weather Table</item>
        <item>Kickoff table</item>
        <item>Skills</item>
        <item>Passing Chart</item>
        <item>Foul Table</item>
        <item>Injury/casualty table</item>
        <item>Nuffle Table</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="weatherTable">Weather Table</string>
    <string name="kickoffTable">Kickoff table</string>
    <string name="skills">Skills</string>
    <string name="offenseOptions">Offense Options</string>
    <string name="passingChart">Passing Chart</string>
    <string name="foulTable">Foul Table</string>
    <string name="injuryTable">Injury/casualty Table</string>
    <string name="nuffleTable">Nuffle Table</string>

    <string-array name="weather_headers_numbers">
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4–10</item>
        <item>11</item>
        <item>12</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="weather2">2</string>
    <string name="weather3">3</string>
    <string name="weather410">4–10</string>
    <string name="weather11">11</string>
    <string name="weather12">12</string>

    <string-array name="weather_descriptions">
        <item>Some players faint in the unbearable heat! D3 randomly selected players from each team that are on the pitch
            when a drive ends are placed in the Reserves box. They must miss the next drive.</item>
        <item>A glorious day, but the clear skies and bright sunlight interfere with the passing game!
        Apply a -1 modifier every time a player tests against their Passing Ability.</item>
        <item>Neither too cold nor too hot. A warm, dry and slightly overcast day provides the perfect conditions for Blood Bowl.</item>
        <item>A torrential downpour leaves the players soaked and the ball very slippery! Apply a -1 modifier
        every time a player makes an Agility test to catch or pick-up the ball, or to attempt to interfere with a pass.</item>
        <item>Freezing conditions and heavy falls of snow make the footing treacherous. Apply a -1 modifier every time a player
            attempts to Rush an extra square. Additionally, the poor visibility means that only Quick and Short passes can be attempted.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="weather_sweltering_full">Some players faint in the unbearable heat! D3 randomly selected players from each team that are on the pitch
            when a drive ends are placed in the Reserves box. They must miss the next drive.</string>
    <string name="weather_sunny_full">A glorious day, but the clear skies and bright sunlight interfere with the passing game!
        Apply a -1 modifier every time a player tests against their Passing Ability.</string>
    <string name="weather_perfect_full">Neither too cold nor too hot. A warm, dry and slightly overcast day provides the perfect conditions for Blood Bowl.</string>
    <string name="weather_rain_full">A torrential downpour leaves the players soaked and the ball very slippery! Apply a -1 modifier
        every time a player makes an Agility test to catch or pick-up the ball, or to attempt to interfere with a pass.</string>
    <string name="weather_blizzard_full">Freezing conditions and heavy falls of snow make the footing treacherous. Apply a -1 modifier every time a player
            attempts to Rush an extra square. Additionally, the poor visibility means that only Quick and Short passes can be attempted.</string>

    <string-array name="weather_titles">
        <item>Sweltering Heat</item>
        <item>Very Sunny</item>
        <item>Perfect Conditions</item>
        <item>Pouring Rain</item>
        <item>Blizzard</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="weather_sweltering_title">Sweltering Heat</string>
    <string name="weather_sunny_title">Very Sunny</string>
    <string name="weather_perfect_title">Perfect Conditions</string>
    <string name="weather_rain_title">Pouring Rain</string>
    <string name="weather_blizzard_title">Blizzard</string>

    <string-array name="kickoff_headers">
        <item>Get the Ref</item>
        <item>Time-out</item>
        <item>Solid Defense</item>
        <item>High Kick</item>
        <item>Cheering Fans</item>
        <item>Brilliant Coaching</item>
        <item>Changing Weather</item>
        <item>Quick Snap</item>
        <item>Blitz</item>
        <item>Officious Ref</item>
        <item>Pitch Invasion</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="kickoff_headers_numbers">
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4</item>
        <item>5</item>
        <item>6</item>
        <item>7</item>
        <item>8</item>
        <item>9</item>
        <item>10</item>
        <item>11</item>
        <item>12</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="kickoff_descriptions">
        <item>Each team gains a free Bribe Inducement. This Inducement must be used before the end of the game or it is lost.</item>
        <item>If the kicking team\'s turn marker is on turn 6, 7, or 8 for the half, both coaches move their turn marker back one
        space. Otherwise, both coaches move their turn marker forward one space.</item>
        <item>D3+3 open players on the kicking team may be removed and set up again in different locations, following all of
        the usual set-up rules.</item>
        <item>One open player on the receiving team may be moved any number of squares, regardless of their MA, and placed in
        the same square the ball will land in.</item>
        <item>Both coaches roll a D6 and add the number of cheerleaders on their Team Draft list. The coach with the highest total may
        immediately roll once on the Prayers to Nuffle table. In the case of a tie, neither coach rolls on the Prayers to Nuffle table.
        Note that if you roll a result that is currently in effect, you must re-roll it.</item>
        <item>Both coaches roll a D6 and add the number of assistant coaches on their Team Draft list. The coach with the highest total gains
        one extra team re-roll for the drive ahead. If this team re-roll is not used before the end of this drive, it is lost. In the case
        of a tie, neither coach gains an extra team re-roll.</item>
        <item>Make a new roll on the Weather Table and apply that result. If the weather conditions are \'Perfect Conditions\' as a result
        of this roll, the ball will scatter before landing.</item>
        <item>D3+3 open players on the receiving team may immediately move one square in any direction.</item>
        <item>D3+3 open players on the kicking team may immediately activate to perform a move action. One may perform a blitz action and one may
        perform throw team-mate action. If a player falls over or is knocked down, no further players can be activated and the blitz ends immediately</item>
        <item>Both coaches roll a D6 and add their Fan Factor to the result. The coach that rolls the lowest randomly selects one of their players
        from among those on the pitch. In the case of a tie, both coaches randomly select a player. Roll a D6 for the selected player(s).
        On a roll of 2+, the player and the ref argue and it comes to blows. The player is placed prone and becomes stunned. On a roll of 1, the
        player is immediately sent off.</item>
        <item>Both coaches roll a D6 and add their fan factor to the result. the coach that rolls the lowest randomly selects D3 of their players
        from among those on the pitch. In the case of a tie, both coaches randomly select D3 players from among on those on the pitch. All of
        the randomly selected players are placed prone and become stunned.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="kickoff2">2</string>
    <string name="kickoffRef">Get The Ref</string>
    <string name="kickoffRefFull">Each team gains a free Bribe Inducement. This Inducement must be used before the end of the game or it is lost</string>
</resources>