<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Blood Bowl Companion</string>
    <string name="app_info">App Info</string>
    <string name="app_home">Home</string>
    <string name="current_version">Version:  1.0.1</string>
    <string name="search">search</string>


    <string name="app_info_text_title">About the Blood Bowl Companion App</string>
    <string name="app_info_description">I made this app to be a quick reference for Blood Bowl players during their game.
    It is to be used alongside the official handbook for when you need to quickly check a table or skill.</string>
    <string name="app_info_disclaimer">This is an unofficial application that is not endorsed in any way by Games Workshop Limited or any of
    its subsidiaries. Blood Bowl is a trademark of Games Workshop Limited. All Rights Reserved to their respective owners.</string>
    <string name="app_info_chart_credit">Credit to the Nuffle Amorical Football (NAF) for the passing chart.</string>
    <string name="app_info_email">Contact: BB.Companion.App@gmail.com</string>

    <string-array name="list_headers">
        <item>Weather Table</item>
        <item>Kickoff table</item>
        <item>Skills</item>
        <item>Passing Chart</item>
        <item>Argue the call table</item>
        <item>Injury/casualty table</item>
        <item>Nuffle Table</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="weatherTable">Weather Table</string>
    <string name="kickoffTable">Kickoff table</string>
    <string name="skills">Skills</string>
    <string name="offenseOptions">Offense Options</string>
    <string name="passingChart">Passing Chart</string>
    <string name="foulTable">Foul Table</string>
    <string name="injuryTable">Injury/casualty Table</string>
    <string name="nuffleTable">Nuffle Table</string>

    <string-array name="weather_headers_numbers">
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4–10</item>
        <item>11</item>
        <item>12</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="weather2">2</string>
    <string name="weather3">3</string>
    <string name="weather410">4–10</string>
    <string name="weather11">11</string>
    <string name="weather12">12</string>

    <string-array name="weather_descriptions">
        <item>Some players faint in the unbearable heat! D3 randomly selected players from each team that are on the pitch
            when a drive ends are placed in the Reserves box. They must miss the next drive.</item>
        <item>A glorious day, but the clear skies and bright sunlight interfere with the passing game!
        Apply a -1 modifier every time a player tests against their Passing Ability.</item>
        <item>Neither too cold nor too hot. A warm, dry and slightly overcast day provides the perfect conditions for Blood Bowl.</item>
        <item>A torrential downpour leaves the players soaked and the ball very slippery! Apply a -1 modifier
        every time a player makes an Agility test to catch or pick-up the ball, or to attempt to interfere with a pass.</item>
        <item>Freezing conditions and heavy falls of snow make the footing treacherous. Apply a -1 modifier every time a player
            attempts to Rush an extra square. Additionally, the poor visibility means that only Quick and Short passes can be attempted.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="weather_sweltering_full">Some players faint in the unbearable heat! D3 randomly selected players from each team that are on the pitch
            when a drive ends are placed in the Reserves box. They must miss the next drive.</string>
    <string name="weather_sunny_full">A glorious day, but the clear skies and bright sunlight interfere with the passing game!
        Apply a -1 modifier every time a player tests against their Passing Ability.</string>
    <string name="weather_perfect_full">Neither too cold nor too hot. A warm, dry and slightly overcast day provides the perfect conditions for Blood Bowl.</string>
    <string name="weather_rain_full">A torrential downpour leaves the players soaked and the ball very slippery! Apply a -1 modifier
        every time a player makes an Agility test to catch or pick-up the ball, or to attempt to interfere with a pass.</string>
    <string name="weather_blizzard_full">Freezing conditions and heavy falls of snow make the footing treacherous. Apply a -1 modifier every time a player
            attempts to Rush an extra square. Additionally, the poor visibility means that only Quick and Short passes can be attempted.</string>

    <string-array name="weather_titles">
        <item>Sweltering Heat</item>
        <item>Very Sunny</item>
        <item>Perfect Conditions</item>
        <item>Pouring Rain</item>
        <item>Blizzard</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="weather_sweltering_title">Sweltering Heat</string>
    <string name="weather_sunny_title">Very Sunny</string>
    <string name="weather_perfect_title">Perfect Conditions</string>
    <string name="weather_rain_title">Pouring Rain</string>
    <string name="weather_blizzard_title">Blizzard</string>

    <string-array name="kickoff_headers">
        <item>Get the Ref</item>
        <item>Time-out</item>
        <item>Solid Defense</item>
        <item>High Kick</item>
        <item>Cheering Fans</item>
        <item>Brilliant Coaching</item>
        <item>Changing Weather</item>
        <item>Quick Snap</item>
        <item>Blitz</item>
        <item>Officious Ref</item>
        <item>Pitch Invasion</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="kickoff_headers_numbers">
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4</item>
        <item>5</item>
        <item>6</item>
        <item>7</item>
        <item>8</item>
        <item>9</item>
        <item>10</item>
        <item>11</item>
        <item>12</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="kickoff_descriptions">
        <item>Each team gains a free Bribe Inducement. This Inducement must be used before the end of the game or it is lost.</item>
        <item>If the kicking team\'s turn marker is on turn 6, 7, or 8 for the half, both coaches move their turn marker back one
        space. Otherwise, both coaches move their turn marker forward one space.</item>
        <item>D3+3 open players on the kicking team may be removed and set up again in different locations, following all of
        the usual set-up rules.</item>
        <item>One open player on the receiving team may be moved any number of squares, regardless of their MA, and placed in
        the same square the ball will land in.</item>
        <item>Both coaches roll a D6 and add the number of cheerleaders on their Team Draft list. The coach with the highest total may
        immediately roll once on the Prayers to Nuffle table. In the case of a tie, neither coach rolls on the Prayers to Nuffle table.
        Note that if you roll a result that is currently in effect, you must re-roll it.</item>
        <item>Both coaches roll a D6 and add the number of assistant coaches on their Team Draft list. The coach with the highest total gains
        one extra team re-roll for the drive ahead. If this team re-roll is not used before the end of this drive, it is lost. In the case
        of a tie, neither coach gains an extra team re-roll.</item>
        <item>Make a new roll on the Weather Table and apply that result. If the weather conditions are \'Perfect Conditions\' as a result
        of this roll, the ball will scatter before landing.</item>
        <item>D3+3 open players on the receiving team may immediately move one square in any direction.</item>
        <item>D3+3 open players on the kicking team may immediately activate to perform a move action. One may perform a blitz action and one may
        perform throw team-mate action. If a player falls over or is knocked down, no further players can be activated and the blitz ends immediately</item>
        <item>Both coaches roll a D6 and add their Fan Factor to the result. The coach that rolls the lowest randomly selects one of their players
        from among those on the pitch. In the case of a tie, both coaches randomly select a player. Roll a D6 for the selected player(s).
        On a roll of 2+, the player and the ref argue and it comes to blows. The player is placed prone and becomes stunned. On a roll of 1, the
        player is immediately sent off.</item>
        <item>Both coaches roll a D6 and add their fan factor to the result. the coach that rolls the lowest randomly selects D3 of their players
        from among those on the pitch. In the case of a tie, both coaches randomly select D3 players from among on those on the pitch. All of
        the randomly selected players are placed prone and become stunned.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="kickoff2">2</string>
    <string name="kickoffRef">Get The Ref</string>
    <string name="kickoffRefFull">Each team gains a free Bribe Inducement. This Inducement must be used before the end of the game or it is lost</string>

    <string-array name="foul_numbers">
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2–5</item>
        <item>6</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="foul_headers">
        <item>You\'re outta here!</item>
        <item>I don\'t care!</item>
        <item>When you put it like that</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="foul_descriptions">
        <item>The referee is so enraged that the coach is ejected along with the player.
        For the remainder of the game, you may no longer Argue The Call and must apply a
        -1 modifier when rolling for brilliant coaching.</item>
        <item>The referee is not interested in your argument. The player is sent-off
        and a turnover caused.</item>
        <item>The referee is swayed by your argument. A Turnover is still caused,
            but the player that committed the foul is not Sent-off.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="foul6">6</string>
    <string name="foulWell"><![CDATA[when you put it like that]]></string>
    <string name="foulWellFull">The referee is swayed by your argument. A Turnover
    is still caused, but the player that committed the foul is not Sent-off.</string>

    <string-array name="injuryTableHeaderList">
        <item>Injury Roll</item>
        <item>Stunty Injury Roll</item>
        <item>Casualty Roll</item>
        <item>Lasting Injury Roll</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="injuryTableHeader">Injury Roll</string>

    <string-array name="injuryRollNumbers">
        <item>2–7</item>
        <item>8–9</item>
        <item>10+</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="injuryRollHeaders">
        <item>Stunned</item>
        <item>KO\'d</item>
        <item>Casualty!</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="injuryRollDescriptions">
        <item>The player immediately becomes stunned, and is laid face-down on the pitch.</item>
        <item>The player is immediately removed from play and placed in the knocked-out box of their team dugout.
        At the end of each drive, there is a chance any knocked-out players will recover.</item>
        <item>The player becomes a casualty and is immediately removed from play and placed in the casualty box of their team dugout.
        The coach of the opposing team immediately makes a casualty roll against the player.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="injuryRoll2">2–7</string>
    <string name="injuryRollStunned">Stunned</string>
    <string name="injuryRollStunnedFull">The player immediately becomes stunned, and is laid face-down on the pitch.</string>

    <string-array name="stuntyRollNumbers">
        <item>2–6</item>
        <item>7–8</item>
        <item>9</item>
        <item>10+</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="stuntyRollHeaders">
        <item>Stunned</item>
        <item>KO\'d</item>
        <item>Badly Hurt</item>
        <item>Casualty!</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="stuntyRollDescriptions">
        <item>The player immediately becomes stunned, and is laid face-down on the pitch.</item>
        <item>The player is immediately removed from play and placed in the knocked-out box of their team dugout.
        At the end of each drive, there is a chance any knocked-out players will recover.</item>
        <item>The player becomes a casualty and is immediately removed from play and placed in casualty box of
        their team dugout. No casualty roll is made. Instead, a badly hurt result is automatically applied.</item>
        <item>The player becomes a casualty and is immediately removed from play and placed in casualty box of
        their team dugout. The coach of the opposing team immediately makes a casualty roll against the player.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="stuntyRoll2">2–6</string>
    <string name="stuntyRollStunned">Stunned</string>
    <string name="stuntyRollStunnedFull">The player immediately becomes stunned, and is laid face-down on the pitch.</string>

    <string-array name="casualtyRollNumbers">
        <item>1–6</item>
        <item>7–9</item>
        <item>10–12</item>
        <item>13–14</item>
        <item>15–16</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="casualtyRollHeaders">
        <item>Badly Hurt</item>
        <item>Seriously Hurt</item>
        <item>Serious Injury</item>
        <item>Lasting Injury</item>
        <item>DEAD</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="casualtyRollDescriptions">
        <item>The player misses the rest of this game, but suffers no long term effect.</item>
        <item>Miss Next Game</item>
        <item>Niggling Injury and Miss Next Game</item>
        <item>Characteristic Reduction and Miss Next Game</item>
        <item>This player is far too dead to play Blood Bowl!</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="casualtyRoll1">1–6</string>
    <string name="casualtyRollBadlyHurt">Badly Hurt</string>
    <string name="casualtyRollBadlyHurtFull">The player misses the rest of this game, but suffers no long term effect.</string>

    <string-array name="lastingRollNumbers">
        <item>1–2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4</item>
        <item>5</item>
        <item>6</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="lastingRollHeaders">
        <item>Head Injury</item>
        <item>Smashed Knee</item>
        <item>Broken Arm</item>
        <item>Neck Injury</item>
        <item>Dislocated Shoulder</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="lastingRollDescriptions">
        <item>-1 Armour Value</item>
        <item>-1 Movement Allowance</item>
        <item>-1 Passing Ability</item>
        <item>-1 Agility</item>
        <item>-1 Strength</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="lastingNumber">1–2</string>
    <string name="lastingHeader">Head Injury</string>
    <string name="lastingDescription">-1 Armour Value</string>

    <string-array name="nuffleTableNumbers">
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4</item>
        <item>5</item>
        <item>6</item>
        <item>7</item>
        <item>8</item>
        <item>9</item>
        <item>10</item>
        <item>11</item>
        <item>12</item>
        <item>13</item>
        <item>14</item>
        <item>15</item>
        <item>16</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="nuffleTableHeaders">
        <item>Treacherous Trapdoor</item>
        <item>Friends with the Ref</item>
        <item>Stiletto</item>
        <item>Iron Man</item>
        <item>Knuckle Dusters</item>
        <item>Bad Habits</item>
        <item>Greasy Cleats</item>
        <item>Blessed Statue of Nuffle</item>
        <item>Moles under the pitch</item>
        <item>Perfect Passing</item>
        <item>Fan Interactions</item>
        <item>Necessary Violence</item>
        <item>Fouling Frenzy</item>
        <item>Throw a rock</item>
        <item>Under Scrutiny</item>
        <item>Intensive Training</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="nuffleTableDescriptions">
        <item>Until the end of this half, every time any player enters a trapdoor square, for any reason, roll a D6. On a roll of 1,
        the trapdoor falls open and the player is immediately removed from play. Treat them exactly as if they had been pushed
        in the crowd. If the player was in possession of the ball, it bounces from the trapdoor square.</item>
        <item>Until the end of this drive, you may treat a roll of 5 or 6 on the argue the call table as a \"well, when you
        put it like that…\" result and a roll of 2-4 as an \"I don\'t care!\" result.</item>
        <item>Randomly select one player on your team that is available to play during this drive and that does not have the
        Loner (X+) trait. Until the end of this drive, that player has the stab trait.</item>
        <item>Choose one player on your team that is available to play during this drive and that does not have the Loner (X+)
        trait. Until the end of this game, that player improves their AV by 1, to a maximum of 11+.</item>
        <item>Choose one player on your team that is available to play during this drive that does not have the Loner (X+)
        trait. Until the end of this drive, that player gains the Mighty Blow (+1) skill.</item>
        <item>Randomly select D3 opposition players that are available to play during this drive that do not have the Loner (X+)
        trait. Until the end of this drive, those players gain the Loner (2+) trait.</item>
        <item>Randomly select one opposition player that is available to play during this drive. That player had their boots
        tampered with! Until the end of this drive, their MA is reduced by 1.</item>
        <item>Choose one player on your team that is available to play during this drive and that does not have the Loner (X+)
        trait. Until the end of this game, the player gains the Pro skill.</item>
        <item>Until the end of this half, apply a -1 modifier every time a player attempts to rush an extra square (-2 should it
        occur that both coaches have rolled this result).</item>
        <item>Until the end of this game, any player on your team that makes a completion earns 2 spp rather than the
        usual 1 spp.</item>
        <item>Until the end of this drive, if a player on your team causes a casualty by pushing an opponent into the crowd,
        that player will earn 2 spp exactly as if they had caused a casualty by performing a block action.</item>
        <item>Until the end of this drive, any player on your team that causes a casualty earns 3 spp, rather than the
        usual 2 spp.</item>
        <item>Until the end of this drive, any player on your team that causes a casualty with a foul action earns 2 spp
        exactly as if they had caused a casualty by performing a block action.</item>
        <item>Until the end of this drive, should an opposition player stall, at the end of their team turn you may roll a D6.
        On a roll of 5+, an angry fan throws a rock at that player. The player is immediately knocked down. </item>
        <item>Until the end of this half, any player on the opposing team that commits a foul action is automatically
        seen by the referee, even if a natural double is not rolled.</item>
        <item>Randomly select one player on your team that is available to play during this drive and that does not have
        the Loner (X+) trait. Until the end of the game, that player gains a single primary skill of your choice.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="nuffleNumber">1</string>
    <string name="nuffleHeader">Treacherous Trapdoor</string>
    <string name="nuffleDescription">Until the end of this half, every time any player enters a trapdoor square, for any reason, roll a D6. On a roll of 1,
        the trapdoor falls open and the player is immediately removed from play. Treat them exactly as if they had been pushed
        in the crowd. If the player was in possession of the ball, it bounces from the trapdoor square.</string>

    <string-array name="skillHeaders">
        <item>Accurate</item>
        <item>Always Hungry*</item>
        <item>Animal Savagery*</item>
        <item>Animosity*</item>
        <item>Arm Bar</item>
        <item>Ball &amp; Chain*</item>
        <item>Big Hand</item>
        <item>Block</item>
        <item>Bloodlust (X+)*</item>
        <item>Bombardier</item>
        <item>Bone Head*</item>
        <item>Brawler</item>
        <item>Break Tackle</item>
        <item>Cannoneer</item>
        <item>Catch</item>
        <item>Chainsaw*</item>
        <item>Claws</item>
        <item>Cloud Burster</item>
        <item>Dauntless</item>
        <item>Decay*</item>
        <item>Defensive</item>
        <item>Dirty Player (+1)</item>
        <item>Disturbing Presence*</item>
        <item>Diving Catch</item>
        <item>Diving Tackle</item>
        <item>Dodge</item>
        <item>Drunkard</item>
        <item>Dump-off</item>
        <item>Extra Arms</item>
        <item>Fend</item>
        <item>Foul Appearance*</item>
        <item>Frenzy*</item>
        <item>Fumblerooskie</item>
        <item>Grab</item>
        <item>Guard</item>
        <item>Hail Mary Pass</item>
        <item>Hit and run</item>
        <item>Horns</item>
        <item>Hypnotic Gaze</item>
        <item>Iron Hard Skin</item>
        <item>Juggernaut</item>
        <item>Jump Up</item>
        <item>Kick Team-mate</item>
        <item>Kick</item>
        <item>Leader</item>
        <item>Leap</item>
        <item>Loner (X+)*</item>
        <item>Mighty Blow (+1)</item>
        <item>Monstrous Mouth</item>
        <item>Multiple Block</item>
        <item>Nerves of Steel</item>
        <item>No Hands*</item>
        <item>On the Ball</item>
        <item>Pass</item>
        <item>Pick-me-up</item>
        <item>Pile Driver</item>
        <item>Plague Ridden</item>
        <item>Pogo Stick</item>
        <item>Prehensile Tail</item>
        <item>Pro</item>
        <item>Projectile Vomit</item>
        <item>Really Stupid*</item>
        <item>Regeneration</item>
        <item>Right Stuff*</item>
        <item>Running Pass</item>
        <item>Safe Pair of Hands</item>
        <item>Safe Pass</item>
        <item>Secret Weapon*</item>
        <item>Shadowing</item>
        <item>Side Step</item>
        <item>Sneaky Git</item>
        <item>Sprint</item>
        <item>Stab</item>
        <item>Stand Firm</item>
        <item>Strip Ball</item>
        <item>Strong Arm</item>
        <item>Stunty*</item>
        <item>Sure Feet</item>
        <item>Sure Hands</item>
        <item>Swarming</item>
        <item>Swoop</item>
        <item>Tackle</item>
        <item>Take Root*</item>
        <item>Tentacles</item>
        <item>Thick Skull</item>
        <item>Throw team-mate</item>
        <item>Timm-ber!</item>
        <item>Titchy*</item>
        <item>Two Heads</item>
        <item>Unchannelled Fury*</item>
        <item>Very Long Legs</item>
        <item>Wrestle</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="skillDescriptions">
        <item><![CDATA[When this player performs a Quick Pass action or a Short Pass action, you may apply an additional +1
        modifier to the Passing Ability test.]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[*Skill is compulsory.\n\nIf this player wishes to perform a Throw Team-Mate action, roll a D6 after they have
        finished moving, but before they throw their team-mate. On a roll of 2+, continue with the throw as normal.
        On a roll of 1, this player will attempt to eat their team-mate. Roll another D6.\n\nOn a roll of 1, the team-mate
        has been eaten and is immediately removed from the Team Draft list. No apothecary can save them and no Regeneration attempts
        can be made. If the team-mate was in possession of the ball, it will bounce from the square this player occupies.\n
        On a roll of 2+, the team-mate squirms free and the Throw Team-Mate action is automatically fumbled.]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nWhen this player is activated, even if they are Prone or have lost their Tackle Zone,
        immediately after declaring the action they will perform but before performing the action, roll a D6, applying a +2
        modifier to the dice roll if you declared the player would perform a Block or Blitz action (or a Special action granted
        by a Skill or Trait that can be performed instead of a Block action).
            \n\nOn a roll of 1-3, this player lashes out at their team-mates:
            \n\nOne Standing team-mate of your choice that is currently adjacent to this player is immediately Knocked Down
        by this player. This does not cause a turnover unless the Knocked Down player was in possession of the ball. After making
        an Armour roll (and possible Injury roll) against the Knocked Down player, this player may continue their activation
        and complete their declared action if able. Note that, if this player has any applicable Skills, the coach of the
        opposing team may use them when making an Armour roll (and possible Injury roll) against the Knocked Down player.
            \n\nIf this player is not currently adjacent to any Standing team-mates, this player\'s activation ends immediately.
        Additionally, this player loses their Tackle Zone until they are next activated.
            \n\nOn a roll of 4+, this player continues their activation as normal and completes their declared action.
            \n\nIf you declared that this player would perform an action which can only be performed once per team turn and
        this player\'s activation ended before the action could be completed, the action is considered to have been performed,
        and no other player on your team may perform the same action this team turn.]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nThis player is jealous of and dislikes certain other players on their team, as shown in brackets after the name
        of the skill on this player\'s profile. This may be defined by position or race.
            \n\nWhen this player wishes to perform a hand-off action to a team-mate of the type listed, or attempts to perform
        a pass action and the target square is occupied by a team-mate of the type listed, this player may refuse to do so.
        Roll a D6. On a roll of 1, this player refuses to perform this action and their activation comes to an end. Animosity does
        not extend to mercenaries or star players.]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[If an opposition player falls over as the result of failing their agility test when attempting to dodge, jump, or
        leap out of a square in which they were being marked by this player, you may apply a +1 modifier to either the armour roll
        or injury roll. This modifier may be applied after the roll has been made and may be applied even if this player is now
        Prone.
            \n\nIf the opposition player was being marked by more than one player with this skill, only one player may use it.]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nWhen this player is activated, the only action they may perform is a \'Ball and Chain Move\' special action.
        There is no limit to how many players with this trait may perform this special action each team turn.
            \n\nWhen this player performs this special action:
            \n-Place the throw-in template over the player, facing towards either end zone or either side line as you wish.
            \n-Roll a D6 and move the player one square in the direction indicated.
            \n-A player with Ball and Chain automatically passes any agility tests they may be required to make in order to dodge,
        regardless of any modifiers.
            \n-If this movement takes the player off the pitch, they risk injury by the crowd.
            \n-If this movement takes the player into a square in which the ball is placed, the player is considered to have moved
        involuntarily. Therefore, they may not attempt to pick the ball up and the ball will bounce.
            \n\nRepeat this process for each square the player moves.
            \n\nIf this player would move into a square that is occupied by a standing player from either team, they must perform
        a block action against that player, following the normal rules, but with the following exceptions:
            \n-A ball and chain player ignores the foul appearance skill.
            \n-A ball and chain player must follow-up if they push-back another player.
            \n\nIf this player moves into a square that is occupied by a prone or stunned player is immediately pushed back and
        an armour roll is made against them.
            \n\nThis player may rush. Declare that the player will rush before placing the throw-in template and rolling the d6
        to determine direction:
            \n-If this player rushes into an unoccupied square, move them as normal and roll a d6:
            \n\t-On a roll of 2+, this player moves without mishap.
            \n\t-On a roll of 1 (before or after modification), the player falls over.
            \n-If this player rushes into a square that is occupied by a standing player from either team, roll a d6:
            \n\t-On a roll of 2+, this player moves without mishap and will perform a block action against the player occupying the
        square as described previously.
            \n\t-On a roll of 1 (before or after modification), the player occupying the square is pushed back and this player
        will fall over after moving into the vacated square.
            \n\nIf this player ever falls over, is knocked down or is placed prone, an injury roll is immediately made against
        them (no armour roll is required), treating a stunned result as a KO\'d result.
            \n\nA player with this trait cannot also have the diving tackle, frenzy, grab, leap, multiple block, on the ball,
        or shadowing skills.
            \n\nThis trait must still be used if the player is prone or has lost their tackle zone.]]></item>
        <item>This player may ignore any modifier(s) for being marked or for pouring rain weather conditions when they
        attempt to pick up the ball.</item>
        <item>When a both down result is applied during a block action, this player may choose to ignore it
        and not be knocked down.</item>
        <item>*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nTo keep control of their wits, vampires need a supply of fresh blood. Whenever a player with this trait
        activates, after declaring their action, they must roll a D6, adding 1 to the roll if they declared a block action
        or a blitz action. If they roll equal to or higher than the number shown in brackets, they may activate as normal.
            \n\nIf the player rolls lower than the number shown in brackets, or rolls a natural 1, they may continue their
        activation as normal though they may change their declared action to a move action if they wish.
            \n\nIf the player declared an action that can only be performed once per team turn (such as a blitz action), this will still count
        as the one of that action for the team turn. At the end of their activation, they may bite an adjacent thrall
        lineman team-mate (standing, prone, or stunned).
            \n\nIf they bite a thrall, immediately make an injury roll for the thrall, treating any casualty result as badly hurt; this will not cause a Turnover unless the thrall was holding the
        ball. If they do not bite a thrall for any reason then a turnover is caused, the player will lose their tackle zone
        until they are next activated, and will immediately drop the ball if they were holding it. If the player was in the
        opposing end zone, no touchdown is scored. If a player who failed this roll wants to make a pass action, hand-off
        or score, then they must bite a thrall before they perform the action or score.</item>
        <item>When activated and if they are standing, this player can perform a \'throw bomb\' special action. This special
        action is neither a pass action nor a throw team-mate action, so does not prevent another player from performing
        one of those actions during the same team turn. However, only a single player with this trait may perform this
        special action each team turn.
            \n\nA bomb can be thrown and caught, and the throw interfered with, just like a ball, using the rules for
        pass actions, with the following exceptions:
            \n\t-A player may not stand up or move before performing a throw bomb action.
            \n\t-Bombs do not bounce and can come to rest on the ground in an occupied square. Should a player fail to
        catch a bomb, it will come to rest on the ground in the square that player occupies.
            \n\t-If a bomb is fumbled, it will explode immediately in the square occupied by the player attempting to throw it.
            \n\t-If a bomb comes to rest on the ground in an empty square or is caught by an opposition player, no
        turnover is caused.
            \n\t-A player that is in possession of the ball can still catch a bomb.
            \n\t-Any skills that can be used when performing a pass action can also be used when performing a throw bomb
        special action, with the exception of on the ball.
            \n\nIf a bomb is caught by a player on either team, roll a D6:
            \n\t-On a roll of 4+, the bomb explodes immediately, as described below.
            \n\t-On a roll of 1-3, that player must throw the bomb again immediately. This throw takes place out of the
        normal sequence of play.
            \n\nShould a bomb ever leave the pitch, it explodes in the crowd with no effect (on the game) before
        the crowd can throw it back.
            \n\nWhen a bomb comes to rest on the ground, in either an unoccupied square, in a square occupied by a player
        that failed to catch the bomb, or in a square occupied by a prone or stunned player, it will explode immediately:
            \n-If the bomb explodes in an occupied square, that player is automatically hit by the explosion.
            \n-Roll a D6 for each player (from either team) that occupies a square adjacent to the one in which
        the bom exploded:
            \n\t-On a roll of 4+, the player has been hit by the explosion.
            \n\t-On a roll of 1-3, the player manages to avoid the explosion.
            \n-An armour roll (and possibly an injury roll as well) is made against any player hit by the explosion,
        even if they were already prone or stunned.
            \n-You may apply a +1 modifier to their the armour roll or injury roll. This modifier may be applied after
        the roll has been made.</item>
        <item>*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nWhen this player is activated, even if they are prone or have lost their tackle zone, immediately
        after declaring the action they will perform but before performing the action, roll a D6:
            \n-On a roll of 1, this player forgets what they are doing and their activation ends immediately.
        Additionally, this player loses their tackle zone until they are next activated.
            \n-On a roll of 2+, this player continues their activation as normal and completes their declared action.
            \n\nIf you declared that this player would perform an action which can only be performed once per team turn
        and this player\'s activation ended before the action could be completed, the action is considered to have been
        performed and no other player on your team may perform the same action this team turn.</item>
        <item>When this player performs a block action on its own (but not as part of a blitz action),
        this player may re-roll a single both down result.</item>
        <item>Once during their activation, after making an agility test in order to dodge, this player may modify the dice
        roll by +1 if their strength characteristic is 4 or less, or by +2 if their strength characteristic is 5 or more.</item>
        <item>When this player performs a long pass action or a long bomb pass action, you may apply an additional +1
        modifier to the passing ability test.</item>
        <item>This player may re-roll a failed agility test when attempting to catch the ball.</item>
        <item>*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nInstead of performing a block action (on its own or as part of a blitz action), this player may perform
        a \'chainsaw attack\' special action. Exactly as described for a block action, nominate a single standing player
        to be the target of a chainsaw attack special action. There is no limit to how many players with this trait
        may perform this special action each team turn.
            \n\nTo perform a chainsaw attack special action, roll a D6:
            \n-On a roll of 2+, the nominated target is hit by a chainsaw!
            \n-On a roll of 1, the chainsaw will violently \'kick-back\' and hit the player wielding it.
            \n-In either case, an armour roll is made against the player hit by the chainsaw, adding +3 to the result.
            \n-If the armour of the player hit is broken, they become prone and an injury roll is made against them.
        This injury roll cannot be modified in any way.
            \n-If the armour of the player hit is not broken, this trait has no effect.
            \n\nThis player can only use the chainsaw once per turn (i.e. a chainsaw cannot be used with frenzy or
        multiple block) and if used a part of a blitz action, this player cannot continue moving after using it.
            \n\nIf this player falls over or is knocked down, the opposing coach may add +3 to the armour roll made
        against the player.
            \n\nIf an opposition player performs a block action targeting this player and a player down! or a Pow! result is
        applied, +3 is added to the armour roll. If a both down result is applied, +3 is added to both armour rolls.
            \n\nFinally, this player may use their chainsaw when they perform a foul action. Roll a d6 for kick-back as
        described above. Once again, an armour roll is made against the player hit by the chainsaw, adding +3 to the score.</item>
        <item>When you make an armour roll against an opposition player that was knocked down as the result of a block
        action performed by this player, a roll of 8+ before applying any modifiers will break their armour, regardless
        or their actual armour value.</item>
        <item>When this player performs a long pass action or a long bomb pass action, you may choose to make the opposing
        coach re-roll a successful attempt to interfere with the pass.</item>
        <item>When this player performs a block action (on its own or as part of a blitz action), if the nominated target
        has a higher strength characteristic than this player before counting offensive or defensive assists but after
        applying any other modifiers, roll a D6 and add this player\'s strength characteristic to the result. If the total
        is higher than the target\'s strength characteristic, this player increases their strength characteristic to be
        equal to that of the target of the block action, before counting offensive or defensive assists, for the duration
        or this block action.
            \n\nIf this player has another skill that allows them to perform more than one block action, such as frenzy,
        they must make a dauntless roll before each separate block action is performed.</item>
        <item>*Skill is compulsory
            \n\nIf this player suffers a casualty result on the injury table, there is a +1 modifier applied to all
        rolls made against this player on the casualty table.</item>
        <item>During your opponent\'s turn (but not during your own team turn), any opposition players being marked
        by this player cannot use the guard skill.</item>
        <item>When this player commits a foul action, either the armour roll or injury roll made against the victim may
        be modified by the amount shown in brackets. This modifier may be applied after the roll has been made.</item>
        <item>*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nWhen an opposition player performs either a pass action, a throw team-mate action, or a throw bomb special
        action, or attempts to either interfere with a pass or to catch the ball, they must apply a -1 modifier to the test
        for each player on your team with this skill that is within three squares of them, even if player with this skill
        is prone, stunned, or has lost their tackle zone.</item>
        <item>This player may attempt to catch the ball if a pass, throw-in, or kick-off causes it to land in a square
        within their tackle zone after scattering or deviating. This skill does not allow this player to attempt to catch
        the ball if it bounces into a square within their tackle zone.
            \n\nAdditionally, this player may apply a +1 modifier to any attempt to catch an accurate pass if
        they occupy the target square.</item>
        <item>Should an active opposition player that is attempting to dodge, jump, or leap in order to vacate a square
        in which they are being marked by this player pass their agility test, you may declare that this player will use
        this skill. Your opponent must immediately subtract 2 from the result of the agility test. This player is then
        placed prone in the square vacated by the opposition player.
            \n\nIf the opposition player was being marked by more than one player with this skill, only one player may use it.</item>
        <item>Once per team turn, during their activation, this player may re-roll a failed agility test when attempting to Dodge.
            \n\nAdditionally, this player may choose to use this skill when they are the target of a block action and a stumble
        result is applied against them.</item>
        <item>*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nThis player suffers a -1 penalty to the dice roll when attempting to rush.</item>
        <item>If this player is nominated as the target of a block action (or a special action granted by a skill or trait
        that can be performed instead of a block action) and if they are in possession or the ball, they may immediately perform
        a quick pass action, interrupting the activation of the opposition player performing the block action (or special
        action) to do so. This quick pass action cannot cause a turnover, but otherwise all of the normal rules for passing the
        ball apply. Once the quick pass action is resolved, the active player performs the block action and their team turn continues.</item>
        <item>This player may apply a +1 modifier when they attempt to pick up or catch the ball, or when they attempt to
        interfere with a pass.</item>
        <item>If this player is pushed back as the result of any block dice result being applied against them, they may choose
        to prevent the player that pushed them back from following-up. However, the player that pushed them back may continue
        to move as part of a blitz action if they have movement allowance remaining or by rushing.
            \n\nThis skill cannot be used when this player is chain-pushed, against a player with ball &amp; chain trait or
        against a player with the juggernaut skill that performed the block action as part of a blitz.</item>
        <item>*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nWhen an opposition player declares a block action targeting this player (on its own or as part or a blitz action),
        or any special action that targets this player, their coach must first roll a D6, even if this player has lost their tackle
        zone. On a roll of 1, the player cannot perform the declared action and the action is wasted.
            \n\nThis skill may still be used if the player is prone, stunned, or has lost their tackle zone.</item>
        <item>*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nEvery time this player performs a block action (on its own or as part of a blitz action), they must follow-up
        if the target is pushed back and if they are able. If the target is still standing after being pushed back, and if this
        player was able to follow-up, this player must them perform a second block action against the same target, again
        following-up if the target is pushed back.
            \n\nIf this player is performing a blitz action, performing a second block action will also cost them one square of
        their movement allowance. If this player has no movement allowance left to perform a second block action, they must
        rush to do so. If they cannot rush, they cannot perform a second block action.
            \n\nNote that if an opposition player in possession of the ball is pushed back into your end zone and is still standing,
        a touchdown will be scored, ending the drive. In this case, the second block action is not performed.
            \n\nA player with this skill cannot also have the grab skill.</item>
        <item>When this player performs a move or blitz action whilst in possession of the ball, they may choose to \'drop\'
        the ball. The ball may be placed in any square the player vacates during their movement and does not bounce.
        No turnover is caused.</item>
        <item>When this player performs a block action (on its own or as part of a blitz action), using this skill prevents
        the target of the block from using the side step skill.
            \n\nAdditionally, when this player performs a block action on its own (but not as part of a blitz action), if
        the target is pushed back, this player may choose any unoccupied square adjacent to the target to push that player
        into. If there are no unoccupied squares, this skill cannot be used.
            \n\nA player with this skill cannot also have the frenzy skill.</item>
        <item>This player can offer both offensive and defensive assists regardless of how many opposition
        players are marking them.</item>
        <item>When this player performs a pass action (or a throw bomb action), the target square can be anywhere on the
        pitch and the range ruler does not need to be used. A Hail Mary Pass is never accurate, regardless of the result
        of the passing ability test it will always be inaccurate at best. A passing ability test is made and can be
        re-rolled as normal in order to determine if the Hail Mary Pass is wildly inaccurate or is fumbled. A Hail
        Mary Pass cannot be interfered with. This skill may not be used in a blizzard.</item>
        <item>After a player with this trait performs a block action, they may immediately move one free square ignoring
        tackle zones so long as they are still standing. They must ensure that after this free move, they are not
        marked by or marking any opposition players.</item>
        <item>When this player performs a block action as part of a blitz action (but not on its own), you may apply
        a +1 modifier to this player\'s strength characteristic. This modifier is applied before counting assists,
        before applying any other strength modifiers and before using any other skills or traits.</item>
        <item>During their activation, this player may perform a \'Hypnotic Gaze\' special action. There is no limit
        to how many players with this trait may perform this special action each team turn.
            \n\nTo perform a hypnotic gaze special action, nominate a single standing opposition player that has not lost
        their tackle zone and that this player is marking. Then make an agility test for this player, applying a -1
        modifier for every (other than the nominated player) that is marking this player. If the test is not passed,
        the nominated player loses their tackle zone until they are next activated.
            \n\nThis player may move before performing this special action, following all of the normal movement rules.
        However, once this special action has been performed, this player may not move further and their activation
        comes to an end.</item>
        <item>The claws skill cannot be used when making an armour roll against this player.
            \n\nThis skill may still be used if the player is prone, stunned, or has lost their tackle zone.</item>
        <item>When this player performs a block action as part of a blitz action (but not on its own), they may choose
        to treat a both down result as a push back result. In addition, when this player performs a block action as
        part of a blitz action, the target of the block action may not use the fend, stand firm, or wrestle skills.</item>
        <item>If this player is prone they may stand up for free (i.e., standing does not cost this player three (3)
        squares of their movement allowance, as it normally would).
            \n\nAdditionally, if this player is prone when activated, they may attempt to jump up and perform a block action.
        This player makes an agility test, applying a +1 modifier. If this test is passed, they stand up and may perform
        a block action. If the test is failed, they remain prone and their activation ends.</item>
        <item>Once per team turn, in addition to another player performing either a pass or throw team-mate action, a
        single player with this trait on the active team can perform a \'kick team-mate\' special action and attempt to
        kick a standing team-mate with the right stuff trait that is in a square adjacent to them.
            \n\nTo perform a kick team-mate special action, follow the rules for throw team-mate actions.
            \n\nHowever, if the kick team-mate special action is fumbled, the kicked player is automatically removed from
        play and an injury roll is made against them, treating a stunned result as a KO\'d result (note that, if the player
        that performed this action also has the mighty blow (+X) skill, the coach of the opposing team may use that skill
        on this injury roll). If the kicked player was in possession of the ball when removed from play, the ball will
        bounce from the square they occupied.</item>
        <item>If this player is nominated to be the kicking player during a kick-off, you may choose to halve the result
        of the D6 to determine the number of squares that the ball deviates, rounding any fractions down.</item>
        <item>A team which has one or more players with this skill gains a single extra team re-roll, called a leader
        re-roll. However, the leader re-roll can only be used if there is at least one player with this skill on the pitch
        (even if the player with this skill is prone, stunned, or has lost their tackle zone). If all players with this skill
        are removed from play before the leader re-roll is used, it is lost. The leader re-roll can be carried over into
        extra time if it is not used, but the team does not receive a new one at the start of extra time. Unlike standard
        team re-rolls, the leader re-roll cannot be lost due to a halfling master chef. Otherwise, the leader re-roll
        is treated just like a normal re-roll.</item>
        <item>During their movement, instead of jumping over a single square that is occupied by a prone or stunned player,
        a player with this skill may choose to leap over any single adjacent square, including unoccupied squares and squares
        occupied by standing players.
            \n\nAdditionally, this player may reduce any negative modifier applied to the agility test when they attempt
        to jump over a prone or stunned player, or to leap over an empty square or a square occupied by a standing player by 1,
        to a minimum of -1.
            \n\nA player with this skill cannot also have the pogo stick trait.</item>
        <item>*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nIf this player wishes to use a team re-roll, roll a D6. If you roll equal to or higher than the target number
        shown in brackets, this player may use the team re-roll as normal. Otherwise, the original result stands without
        being re-rolled but the team re-roll is lost just as if it had been used.
            \n\nThis trait must still be used if the player is prone or has lost their tackle zone.</item>
        <item>When an opposition player is knocked down, as the result of a block action performed by this player (on its
        own or as part of a blitz action), you may modify either the armour roll or injury roll by the amount shown in
        brackets. This modifier may be applied after the roll has been made.
            \n\nThis skill cannot be used with the stab or chainsaw traits.</item>
        <item>This player may re-roll any failed attempt to catch the ball. In addition, the strip ball skill
        cannot be used against this player.</item>
        <item>When this player performs a block action on its own (but not as part of a blitz action), they may choose
        to perform two block actions, each targeting a different player they are marking. However, doing so will reduce this
        player\'s strength characteristic by 2 for the duration of this activation. Both block actions are performed
        simultaneously, meaning both are resolved in full even if one or both result in turnover. The dice rolls for
        each block action should be kept separate to avoid confusion. This player cannot follow-up when using this skill.
            \n\nNote that choosing to use this skill means this player will be unable to use the frenzy skill during
        the same activation.</item>
        <item>This player may ignore any modifier(s) for being marked when they attempt to perform a pass action,
        attempt to catch the ball, or attempt to interfere with a pass.</item>
        <item>*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nThis player is unable to take possession of the ball. They may not attempt to pick it up, to catch it,
        or to attempt to interfere with a pass. Any attempt to do so will automatically fail, causing the ball to
        bounce. Should this player voluntarily move into a square in which the ball is placed, they cannot attempt
        to pick it up. The ball will bounce and a turnover is caused if this player had failed an attempt to
        pick up the ball.</item>
        <item>This player may move up to three squares (regardless of their MA), following all of the normal movement rules,
        when the opposing coach declares that one of their players is going to perform a pass action. This move is made after
        the range has been measured and the target square declared, but before the active player makes a passing ability test.
        Making this move interrupts the activation of the opposition player performing the pass action. A player may use this skill
        when an opposition player uses the dump-off skill, but should this player fall over whilst moving, a turnover is caused.
            \n\nAdditionally, during each start of drive sequence, after step 2 but before step 3, one open player with this skill
        on the receiving team may move up to three squares (regardless of them MA). This skill may not be used if a touchback is
        caused when the kick deviates and does not allow the player to cross into their opponent\'s half of the pitch.</item>
        <item>This player may re-roll a failed passing ability test when performing a pass action.</item>
        <item>At the end of the opposition\'s team turn, roll a D6 for each prone, non-stunned team-mate within three
        squares of a standing player with this trait. On a 5+, the prone player may immediately stand up.</item>
        <item>When an opposition player is knocked down by this player as a result of a block action (on its own or
        as part of a blitz action), this player may immediately commit a free foul action against the knocked down
        player. To use this skill, this player must be standing after the block dice result has been selected and
        applied, and must occupy a square adjacent to the knocked down player. After using this skill, the player is
        placed prone and their activation ends immediately.</item>
        <item>Once per game, if an opposition player with a strength characteristic of 4 or less that does not have the
        decay, regeneration, or stunty traits suffers a casualty result of 15-16 (dead) as the result of a block action
        performed or a foul action committed by a player with this trait that belongs to your team, and if that player
        cannot be saved by an apothecary, you may choose to use this trait. If you do, that player does not die; they
        have instead been infected with virulent plague!
            \n\nIf your team has the \'favoured of nurlge\' special rule, a new \'rotten lineman\' player, drawn from the
        nurlge roster, can be placed immediately in the reserves box of your team\'s dugout (this may cause a team to have
        more than 16 players for the remainder of this game). During step 4 of the post-game sequence, this player may be
        permanently hired, exactly as you would a journeyman player that had played for your team.</item>
        <item>During their movement, instead of jumping over a single square that is occupied by a prone or stunned player,
        a player with this trait may choose to leap over any adjacent square, including unoccupied squares and occupied
        by standing players.
            \n\nAdditionally, when this player makes an agility test to jump over a prone or stunned player, or to leap over
        a prone or stunned player, or to leap over an empty square or a square occupied by a standing player, they may ignore
        any negative modifiers that would normally be applied for being marked in the square they jumped or leaped from and/or
        for being marked in the square they have jumped or leaped into.
            \n\nA  player with this trait cannot also have the leap skill.</item>
        <item>When an active opposition player attempts to dodge, jump, or leap in order to vacate a square in which they are being
        marked by this player, there is an additional -1 modifier applied to the active player\'s agility test.
            \n\nIf the opposition player is being marked by more than one player with this mutation, only one player may use it.</item>
        <item>During their activation, this player may attempt to re-roll one dice. This dice may have been rolled either as a single dice roll,
        as part of a multiple dice roll, or as part of a dice pool, but cannot be a dice that was rolled as part of an armour, injury, or casualty roll.
            \n\nRoll a D6:
            \n-On a roll of 3+, the dice can be re-rolled.
            \n-On a roll of 1 or 2, the dice cannot be re-rolled.
            \n\nOnce this player has attempted to use this skill, they may not use a re-roll from any other source to re-roll this one dice.</item>
        <item>Instead of performing a block action (on its own or as part of a blitz action), this player may perform a \'projectile vomit\'
        special action. Exactly as described for a block action, nominate a single standing player to be the target of the projectile vomit
        special action. There is no limit to how many players with this trait may perform this special action each team turn.
            \n\nTo perform a projectile vomit special action, roll a D6:
            \n-On a roll of 2+, this player regurgitates acidic bile onto the nominated player.
            \n-On a roll of 1, this player belches and snorts, before covering itself in acidic bile.
            \n-In either case, an Armour roll is made against the player hit by the projectile vomit. This armour roll cannot be modified in any way.
            \n-If the armour of the player hit is broken, they become prone and an injury roll is made against them. This injury roll
        cannot be modified in any way.
            \n-If the armour of the player hit is not broken, this trait has not effect.
            \n\nA player can only perform this special action once per turn (i.e. projectile vomit cannot be used with frenzy or multiple block).</item>
        <item>*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nWhen this player is activated, even if they are prone or have lost their tackle zone, immediately after declaring the action they will perform
        but before performing the action, roll a D6, applying a +2 modifier to the dice roll if this player is currently adjacent to one or more standing
        team-mates that do not have this trait:
            \n-On a roll of 1-3, this player forgets what they are doing and their activation ends immediately. Additionally, this player loses their
        tackle zone until they are next activated.
            \n-On a roll of 4+, this player continues their activation as normal and completes their declared action.
            \n\nNote that if you declared that this player would perform an action which can only be performed once per team turn and this player\'s
        activation ended before the action could be completed, the action is considered to have been performed and no other player on your team may
        perform the same action this team turn.</item>
        <item>After a casualty roll has been made against this player, roll a D6. On a roll of 4+, the casualty roll is discarded without effect
        and the player is placed in the reserves box rather than the casualty box of their team dugout. On a roll of 1-3, however, the result
        of the casualty roll is applied as normal.
            \n\nThis trait may be used if the player is prone, stunned, or has lost their tackle zone.</item>
        <item>*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nIf this player also has strength characteristic of 3 or less, they can be thrown by team-mate with the throw team-mate skill.
            \n\nThis trait may still be used if the player is prone, stunned, or has lost their tackle zone.</item>
        <item>If this player performs a quick pass action, their activation does not have to end once the pass is resolved. If you wish and
        this player has not used their full movement allowance, they may continue to move after resolving the pass.</item>
        <item>If this player is knocked down or placed prone (but not if they fall over) whilst in possession of the ball, the ball does not
        bounce. Instead, you may place the ball in an unoccupied square adjacent to the one this player occupies when they become prone.
            \n\nThis skill may still be used if the player is prone.</item>
        <item>Should this player fumble a pass action, the ball is not dropped, does not bounce from the square this player occupies, and no
        turnover is caused. Instead, this player retains possession of the ball and their activation ends.</item>
        <item>*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nWhen a drive in which this player took part ends, even if this player was not on the pitch at the end of the drive, this player
        will be sent-off for committing a foul.</item>
        <item>This player can use this skill when an opposition player they are marking voluntarily moves out of a square within this player\'s
        tackle zone. Roll a D6, adding the MA of this player to the roll and then subtracting the MA of the opposition player. If the result is
        6 or higher, or if the roll is a natural 6, this player may immediately move into the square vacated by the opposition player (this player
        does not need to dodge to make this move). If, however, the result is 5 or lower, or if the roll is a natural 1, this skill has no further effect.
            \n\nA player may use this skill any number of times per turn, during either team\'s turn. If an opposition player is being marked by more than
        one player with this skill, only one player may use it.</item>
        <item>If this player is pushed back for any reason, they are not moved into a square chosen by the opposing coach. Instead, you may choose any
        unoccupied square adjacent to this player. This player is pushed back into that square instead. If there are no unoccupied squares adjacent to
        this player, this skill cannot be used.</item>
        <item>When this player performs a foul action, they are not sent-off for committing a foul should they roll a natural double on the armour roll.
            \n\nAdditionally, the activation of this player does not have to end once the foul has been committed. If you wish and if this player has not
        used their full movement allowance, they may continue to move after committing the foul.</item>
        <item>When this player performs any action that includes movement, they may attempt to rush three times, rather than the usual two.</item>
        <item>Instead of performing a block action (on its own or as part of a blitz action), this player may perform a \'stab\' special action.
        Exactly as described for a block action, nominate a single standing player to be the target of the stab special action. There is no limit to
        how many players with this trait may perform this special action each team turn.
            \n\nTo perform a stab special action, make an unmodified armour roll against the target:
            \n-If the armour of the player hit is broken, they become prone and an injury roll is made against them. This injury roll cannot be
        modified in any way.
            \n-If the armour of the player hit is not broken, this trait has no effect.
            \n-If stab is used as part of a blitz action, the player cannot continue moving after using it.</item>
        <item>This player may choose not to be pushed back, either as the result of a block action made against them or by a chain-push.
        Using this skill does not prevent an opposition player with frenzy skill from performing a second block action if this player
        is still standing after the first.</item>
        <item>When this player targets an opposition player that is in possession of the ball with a block action (on its own or
        as part of a blitz action), choosing to apply a push back result will cause that player to drop the ball in the square
        they are pushed back into. The ball will bounce from the square the player is pushed back into, as if they had been knocked down.</item>
        <item>This player may apply a +1 modifier to any passing ability test rolls they make when performing a throw team-mate action.
            \n\nA player that does not have the throw team-mate trait cannot have this skill.</item>
        <item>*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nWhen this player makes an agility test in order to dodge, they ignore any -1 modifiers for being marked in the square
        they have moved into, unless they also have either bombardier trait, the chainsaw trait, or the swoop trait.
            \n\nHowever, when an opposition player attempts to interfere with a pass action performed by this player, that player
        may apply a +1 modifier to their agility test.
            \n\nFinally, players with this trait are more prone to injury. Therefore, when an injury roll is made against this player,
        roll 2D6 and consult the stunty injury table.
            \n\nThis trait must still be used if the player is prone, stunned, or has lost their tackle zone.</item>
        <item>Once per turn, during their activation, this player may re-roll the D6 when attempting to rush.</item>
        <item>This player may re-roll any failed attempt to pick up the ball. In addition, the strip ball skill cannot be
        used against a player with this skill.</item>
        <item>During each start of drive sequence, after Step 2 but before step 3, you may remove D3 players with this trait from reserves box
        of your dugout and set them up on the pitch, allowing you to set up more than the usual 11 players. These extra players may not be placed
        on the line of scrimmage or in a wide zone.</item>
        <item>If this player is thrown by a team-mate, they do not scatter before landing as they normally would. Instead, you may place the
        throw-in template over the player, facing towards either end zone or either sideline as you wish. The player then moves from the target
        square D3 squares in a direction determined by roll a D6 and referring to the throw-in template.</item>
        <item>When an active opposition player attempts to dodge from a square in which they were being marked by one or more players on
        your team with this skill, that player cannot use the dodge skill.
            \n\nAdditionally, when an opposition player is targeted by a block action performed by a player with this skill, that player cannot
        use the dodge skill if a stumble result is applied against them.</item>
        <item>*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nWhen this player is activated, even if they are prone or have lost their tackle zone, immediately after declaring the action
        they will perform but before performing the action, roll a D6:
            \n-A rooted player cannot move from the square they currently occupy for any reason, voluntarily or otherwise, until the end
        of this drive, or until they are knocked down or placed prone.
            \n-A rooted player may perform any action available to them provided they can do so without moving. For example, a rooted player
        may perform a pass action but may not move before making the pass, and so on.
            \n-On a roll of 2+, this player continues their activation as normal.
            \n\nIf you declared that this player would perform any action that includes movement (pass, hand-off, blitz, or foul) prior to them
        becoming rooted, they may complete the action if possible. If they cannot, the action is considered to have been performed and no other
        player on your team may perform the same action this team turn.</item>
        <item>This player can use this skill when an opposition player they are marking voluntarily moves out of a square within this player\'s
        tackle zone. Roll a D6, adding the ST of this player to the roll and then subtracting the ST of the opposition player. If the result is
        6 or higher, or if the roll is a natural 6, the opposition player is held firmly in place and their movement comes to an end. If, however,
        the result is 5 or lower, or if the roll is a natural 1, this skill has no further effect.
            \n\nA player may use this skill any number of times per turn, during either team\'s turn. If an opposition player is being marked by more
        than one player with this skill, only one player may use it.</item>
        <item>When an injury roll is made against this player (even if this player is prone, stunned, or has lost their tackle zone), they can only
        be KO\'d on a roll of 9, and will treat a roll of 8 as a stunned result. If this player also has the stunty trait, they can only be KO\'d
        on a roll of 8, and will treat a roll of 7 as a Stunned result. All other results are unaffected.</item>
        <item>If this player also has a strength characteristic of 5 or more, they may perform a throw team-mate action, allowing them to
        throw a team-mate with the right stuff trait.</item>
        <item>If this player has a movement allowance of 2 or less, apply a +1 modifier to the dice roll when they attempt to stand up for each
        open, standing team-mate they are currently adjacent to. A natural 1 is always a failure, no matter how many team-mates are helping.
            \n\nThis trait may still be used if the player is prone or has lost their tackle zone.</item>
        <item>*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nThis player may apply a +1 modifier to any agility tests they make in order to dodge. However, if an opposition player dodges
        into a square within the tackle zone of this player, this player does not count as marking the moving player for the purposes
        of calculating agility test modifiers.</item>
        <item>This player may apply a +1 modifier to the agility test when they attempt to dodge.</item>
        <item>*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nWhen this player is activated, even if they are prone or have lost their tackle zone, immediately after declaring the
        action they will perform but before performing the action, roll a D6, applying a +2 modifier to the dice roll if you declared
        the player would perform a block or blitz action (or a special action granted by a skill or trait that can be performed
        instead of a block action):
            \n-On a roll of 1-3, this player rages incoherently at others but achieves little else. Their activation ends immediately.
            \n-On a roll of 4+, this player continues their activation as normal and completes their declared action.
            \n\nIf you declared that this player would perform an action which can only be performed once per team turn and this
        player\'s activation ended before the action could be completed, the action is considered to have been performed and
        no other player on your team may perform the same action this team turn.</item>
        <item>This player may reduce any negative modifier applied to the agility test when they attempt to jump over a prone or
        stunned player (or to leap over an empty square or square occupied by a standing player, if this player has the leap skill)
        by 1, to a minimum of -1.
            \n\nAdditionally, this player may apply a +2 modifier to any attempts to interfere with a pass they make.
            \n\nFinally, this player ignores the cloud burster skill.</item>
        <item>This player may use this skill when a both down result is applied, either when they perform a block action or when
        they are the target of a block action. Instead of applying the both down result as normal, and regardless of any other skill
        either player may possess, both players are placed prone.</item>
    </string-array>
    
    <string name="skillBloodlust">Bloodlust (X+)*</string>
    <string name="skillBloodlustFull">*Skill is compulsory.
            \n\nTo keep control of their wits, vampires need a supply of fresh blood. Whenever a player with this trait
        activates, after declaring their action, they must roll a D6, adding 1 to the roll if they declared a block action
        or a blitz action. If they roll equal to or higher than the number shown in brackets, they may activate as normal.
            \n\nIf the player rolls lower than the number shown in brackets, or rolls a natural 1, they may continue their
        activation as normal though they may change their declared action to a move action if they wish. If the player
        declared an action that can only be performed once per team turn (such as a blitz action), this will still count
        as the one of that action for the team turn. At the end of their activation, they may bite an adjacent thrall
        lineman team-mate (standing, prone, or stunned). If they bite a thrall, immediately make an injury roll for the
        thrall, treating any casualty result as badly hurt; this will not cause a turnover unless the thrall was holding the
        ball. If they do not bite a thrall for any reason then a turnover is caused, the player will lose their tackle zone
        until they are next activated, and will immediately drop the ball if they were holding it. If the player was in the
        opposing end zone, no touchdown is scored. If a player who failed this roll wants to make a pass action, hand-off
        or score, then they must bite a thrall before they perform the action or score.</string>
</resources>