<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Blood Bowl Companion</string>
    <string name="app_info">App Info</string>
    <string name="app_home">Home</string>
    <string name="current_version">Version:  1.0.0</string>


    <string name="app_info_text_title">About the Blood Bowl Companion App</string>
    <string name="app_info_description">I made this app to be a quick reference for Blood Bowl players during their game.
    It is to be used alongside the official handbook for when you need to quickly check a table or skill.</string>
    <string name="app_info_disclaimer">This is an unofficial application that is not endorsed in any way by Games Workshop Limited or any of
    its subsidiaries. Blood Bowl is a trademark of Games Workshop Limited. All Rights Reserved to their respective owners.</string>
    <string name="app_info_chart_credit">Credit to the Nuffle Amorical Football (NAF) for the passing chart.</string>

    <string-array name="list_headers">
        <item>Weather Table</item>
        <item>Kickoff table</item>
        <item>Skills</item>
        <item>Passing Chart</item>
        <item>Foul Table</item>
        <item>Injury/casualty table</item>
        <item>Nuffle Table</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="weatherTable">Weather Table</string>
    <string name="kickoffTable">Kickoff table</string>
    <string name="skills">Skills</string>
    <string name="offenseOptions">Offense Options</string>
    <string name="passingChart">Passing Chart</string>
    <string name="foulTable">Foul Table</string>
    <string name="injuryTable">Injury/casualty Table</string>
    <string name="nuffleTable">Nuffle Table</string>

    <string-array name="weather_headers_numbers">
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4–10</item>
        <item>11</item>
        <item>12</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="weather2">2</string>
    <string name="weather3">3</string>
    <string name="weather410">4–10</string>
    <string name="weather11">11</string>
    <string name="weather12">12</string>

    <string-array name="weather_descriptions">
        <item>Some players faint in the unbearable heat! D3 randomly selected players from each team that are on the pitch
            when a drive ends are placed in the Reserves box. They must miss the next drive.</item>
        <item>A glorious day, but the clear skies and bright sunlight interfere with the passing game!
        Apply a -1 modifier every time a player tests against their Passing Ability.</item>
        <item>Neither too cold nor too hot. A warm, dry and slightly overcast day provides the perfect conditions for Blood Bowl.</item>
        <item>A torrential downpour leaves the players soaked and the ball very slippery! Apply a -1 modifier
        every time a player makes an Agility test to catch or pick-up the ball, or to attempt to interfere with a pass.</item>
        <item>Freezing conditions and heavy falls of snow make the footing treacherous. Apply a -1 modifier every time a player
            attempts to Rush an extra square. Additionally, the poor visibility means that only Quick and Short passes can be attempted.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="weather_sweltering_full">Some players faint in the unbearable heat! D3 randomly selected players from each team that are on the pitch
            when a drive ends are placed in the Reserves box. They must miss the next drive.</string>
    <string name="weather_sunny_full">A glorious day, but the clear skies and bright sunlight interfere with the passing game!
        Apply a -1 modifier every time a player tests against their Passing Ability.</string>
    <string name="weather_perfect_full">Neither too cold nor too hot. A warm, dry and slightly overcast day provides the perfect conditions for Blood Bowl.</string>
    <string name="weather_rain_full">A torrential downpour leaves the players soaked and the ball very slippery! Apply a -1 modifier
        every time a player makes an Agility test to catch or pick-up the ball, or to attempt to interfere with a pass.</string>
    <string name="weather_blizzard_full">Freezing conditions and heavy falls of snow make the footing treacherous. Apply a -1 modifier every time a player
            attempts to Rush an extra square. Additionally, the poor visibility means that only Quick and Short passes can be attempted.</string>

    <string-array name="weather_titles">
        <item>Sweltering Heat</item>
        <item>Very Sunny</item>
        <item>Perfect Conditions</item>
        <item>Pouring Rain</item>
        <item>Blizzard</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="weather_sweltering_title">Sweltering Heat</string>
    <string name="weather_sunny_title">Very Sunny</string>
    <string name="weather_perfect_title">Perfect Conditions</string>
    <string name="weather_rain_title">Pouring Rain</string>
    <string name="weather_blizzard_title">Blizzard</string>

    <string-array name="kickoff_headers">
        <item>Get the Ref</item>
        <item>Time-out</item>
        <item>Solid Defense</item>
        <item>High Kick</item>
        <item>Cheering Fans</item>
        <item>Brilliant Coaching</item>
        <item>Changing Weather</item>
        <item>Quick Snap</item>
        <item>Blitz</item>
        <item>Officious Ref</item>
        <item>Pitch Invasion</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="kickoff_headers_numbers">
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4</item>
        <item>5</item>
        <item>6</item>
        <item>7</item>
        <item>8</item>
        <item>9</item>
        <item>10</item>
        <item>11</item>
        <item>12</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="kickoff_descriptions">
        <item>Each team gains a free Bribe Inducement. This Inducement must be used before the end of the game or it is lost.</item>
        <item>If the kicking team\'s turn marker is on turn 6, 7, or 8 for the half, both coaches move their turn marker back one
        space. Otherwise, both coaches move their turn marker forward one space.</item>
        <item>D3+3 open players on the kicking team may be removed and set up again in different locations, following all of
        the usual set-up rules.</item>
        <item>One open player on the receiving team may be moved any number of squares, regardless of their MA, and placed in
        the same square the ball will land in.</item>
        <item>Both coaches roll a D6 and add the number of cheerleaders on their Team Draft list. The coach with the highest total may
        immediately roll once on the Prayers to Nuffle table. In the case of a tie, neither coach rolls on the Prayers to Nuffle table.
        Note that if you roll a result that is currently in effect, you must re-roll it.</item>
        <item>Both coaches roll a D6 and add the number of assistant coaches on their Team Draft list. The coach with the highest total gains
        one extra team re-roll for the drive ahead. If this team re-roll is not used before the end of this drive, it is lost. In the case
        of a tie, neither coach gains an extra team re-roll.</item>
        <item>Make a new roll on the Weather Table and apply that result. If the weather conditions are \'Perfect Conditions\' as a result
        of this roll, the ball will scatter before landing.</item>
        <item>D3+3 open players on the receiving team may immediately move one square in any direction.</item>
        <item>D3+3 open players on the kicking team may immediately activate to perform a move action. One may perform a blitz action and one may
        perform throw team-mate action. If a player falls over or is knocked down, no further players can be activated and the blitz ends immediately</item>
        <item>Both coaches roll a D6 and add their Fan Factor to the result. The coach that rolls the lowest randomly selects one of their players
        from among those on the pitch. In the case of a tie, both coaches randomly select a player. Roll a D6 for the selected player(s).
        On a roll of 2+, the player and the ref argue and it comes to blows. The player is placed prone and becomes stunned. On a roll of 1, the
        player is immediately sent off.</item>
        <item>Both coaches roll a D6 and add their fan factor to the result. the coach that rolls the lowest randomly selects D3 of their players
        from among those on the pitch. In the case of a tie, both coaches randomly select D3 players from among on those on the pitch. All of
        the randomly selected players are placed prone and become stunned.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="kickoff2">2</string>
    <string name="kickoffRef">Get The Ref</string>
    <string name="kickoffRefFull">Each team gains a free Bribe Inducement. This Inducement must be used before the end of the game or it is lost</string>

    <string-array name="foul_numbers">
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2–5</item>
        <item>6</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="foul_headers">
        <item>You\'re outta here!</item>
        <item>I don\'t care!</item>
        <item>When you put it like that</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="foul_descriptions">
        <item>The referee is so enraged that the coach is ejected along with the player.
        For the remainder of the game, you may no longer Argue The Call and must apply a
        -1 modifier when rolling for brilliant coaching.</item>
        <item>The referee is not interested in your argument. The player is sent-off
        and a turnover caused.</item>
        <item>The referee is swayed by your argument. A Turnover is still caused,
            but the player that committed the foul is not Sent-off.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="foul6">6</string>
    <string name="foulWell"><![CDATA[when you put it like that]]></string>
    <string name="foulWellFull">The referee is swayed by your argument. A Turnover
    is still caused, but the player that committed the foul is not Sent-off.</string>

    <string-array name="injuryTableHeaderList">
        <item>Injury Roll</item>
        <item>Stunty Injury Roll</item>
        <item>Casualty Roll</item>
        <item>Lasting Injury Roll</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="injuryTableHeader">Injury Roll</string>

    <string-array name="injuryRollNumbers">
        <item>2–7</item>
        <item>8–9</item>
        <item>10+</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="injuryRollHeaders">
        <item>Stunned</item>
        <item>KO\'d</item>
        <item>Casualty!</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="injuryRollDescriptions">
        <item>The player immediately becomes stunned, and is laid face-down on the pitch.</item>
        <item>The player is immediately removed from play and placed in the knocked-out box of their team dugout.
        At the end of each drive, there is a chance any knocked-out players will recover.</item>
        <item>The player becomes a casualty and is immediately removed from play and placed in the casualty box of their team dugout.
        The coach of the opposing team immediately makes a casualty roll against the player.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="injuryRoll2">2–7</string>
    <string name="injuryRollStunned">Stunned</string>
    <string name="injuryRollStunnedFull">The player immediately becomes stunned, and is laid face-down on the pitch.</string>

    <string-array name="stuntyRollNumbers">
        <item>2–6</item>
        <item>7–8</item>
        <item>9</item>
        <item>10+</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="stuntyRollHeaders">
        <item>Stunned</item>
        <item>KO\'d</item>
        <item>Badly Hurt</item>
        <item>Casualty!</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="stuntyRollDescriptions">
        <item>The player immediately becomes stunned, and is laid face-down on the pitch.</item>
        <item>The player is immediately removed from play and placed in the knocked-out box of their team dugout.
        At the end of each drive, there is a chance any knocked-out players will recover.</item>
        <item>The player becomes a casualty and is immediately removed from play and placed in casualty box of
        their team dugout. No casualty roll is made. Instead, a badly hurt result is automatically applied.</item>
        <item>The player becomes a casualty and is immediately removed from play and placed in casualty box of
        their team dugout. The coach of the opposing team immediately makes a casualty roll against the player.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="stuntyRoll2">2–6</string>
    <string name="stuntyRollStunned">Stunned</string>
    <string name="stuntyRollStunnedFull">The player immediately becomes stunned, and is laid face-down on the pitch.</string>

    <string-array name="casualtyRollNumbers">
        <item>1–6</item>
        <item>7–9</item>
        <item>10–12</item>
        <item>13–14</item>
        <item>15–16</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="casualtyRollHeaders">
        <item>Badly Hurt</item>
        <item>Seriously Hurt</item>
        <item>Serious Injury</item>
        <item>Lasting Injury</item>
        <item>DEAD</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="casualtyRollDescriptions">
        <item>The player misses the rest of this game, but suffers no long term effect.</item>
        <item>Miss Next Game</item>
        <item>Niggling Injury and Miss Next Game</item>
        <item>Characteristic Reduction and Miss Next Game</item>
        <item>This player is far too dead to play Blood Bowl!</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="casualtyRoll1">1–6</string>
    <string name="casualtyRollBadlyHurt">Badly Hurt</string>
    <string name="casualtyRollBadlyHurtFull">The player misses the rest of this game, but suffers no long term effect.</string>

    <string-array name="lastingRollNumbers">
        <item>1–2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4</item>
        <item>5</item>
        <item>6</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="lastingRollHeaders">
        <item>Head Injury</item>
        <item>Smashed Knee</item>
        <item>Broken Arm</item>
        <item>Neck Injury</item>
        <item>Dislocated Shoulder</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="lastingRollDescriptions">
        <item>-1 Armour Value</item>
        <item>-1 Movement Allowance</item>
        <item>-1 Passing Ability</item>
        <item>-1 Agility</item>
        <item>-1 Strength</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="lastingNumber">1–2</string>
    <string name="lastingHeader">Head Injury</string>
    <string name="lastingDescription">-1 Armour Value</string>

    <string-array name="nuffleTableNumbers">
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4</item>
        <item>5</item>
        <item>6</item>
        <item>7</item>
        <item>8</item>
        <item>9</item>
        <item>10</item>
        <item>11</item>
        <item>12</item>
        <item>13</item>
        <item>14</item>
        <item>15</item>
        <item>16</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="nuffleTableHeaders">
        <item>Treacherous Trapdoor</item>
        <item>Friends with the Ref</item>
        <item>Stiletto</item>
        <item>Iron Man</item>
        <item>Knuckle Dusters</item>
        <item>Bad Habits</item>
        <item>Greasy Cleats</item>
        <item>Blessed Statue of Nuffle</item>
        <item>Moles under the pitch</item>
        <item>Perfect Passing</item>
        <item>Fan Interactions</item>
        <item>Necessary Violence</item>
        <item>Fouling Frenzy</item>
        <item>Throw a rock</item>
        <item>Under Scrutiny</item>
        <item>Intensive Training</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="nuffleTableDescriptions">
        <item>Until the end of this half, every time any player enters a trapdoor square, for any reason, roll a D6. On a roll of 1,
        the trapdoor falls open and the player is immediately removed from play. Treat them exactly as if they had been pushed
        in the crowd. If the player was in possession of the ball, it bounces from the trapdoor square.</item>
        <item>Until the end of this drive, you may treat a roll of 5 or 6 on the argue the call table as a \"well, when you
        put it like that…\" result and a roll of 2-4 as an \"I don\'t care!\" result.</item>
        <item>Randomly select one player on your team that is available to play during this drive and that does not have the
        Loner (X+) trait. Until the end of this drive, that player has the stab trait.</item>
        <item>Choose one player on your team that is available to play during this drive and that does not have the Loner (X+)
        trait. Until the end of this game, that player improves their AV by 1, to a maximum of 11+.</item>
        <item>Choose one player on your team that is available to play during this drive that does not have the Loner (X+)
        trait. Until the end of this drive, that player gains the Mighty Blow (+1) skill.</item>
        <item>Randomly select D3 opposition players that are available to play during this drive that do not have the Loner (X+)
        trait. Until the end of this drive, those players gain the Loner (2+) trait.</item>
        <item>Randomly select one opposition player that is available to play during this drive. That player had their boots
        tampered with! Until the end of this drive, their MA is reduced by 1.</item>
        <item>Choose one player on your team that is available to play during this drive and that does not have the Loner (X+)
        trait. Until the end of this game, the player gains the Pro skill.</item>
        <item>Until the end of this half, apply a -1 modifier every time a player attempts to rush an extra square (-2 should it
        occur that both coaches have rolled this result).</item>
        <item>Until the end of this game, any player on your team that makes a completion earns 2 spp rather than the
        usual 1 spp.</item>
        <item>Until the end of this drive, if a player on your team causes a casualty by pushing an opponent into the crowd,
        that player will earn 2 spp exactly as if they had caused a casualty by performing a block action.</item>
        <item>Until the end of this drive, any player on your team that causes a casualty earns 3 spp, rather than the
        usual 2 spp.</item>
        <item>Until the end of this drive, any player on your team that causes a casualty with a foul action earns 2 spp
        exactly as if they had caused a casualty by performing a block action.</item>
        <item>Until the end of this drive, should an opposition player stall, at the end of their team turn you may roll a D6.
        On a roll of 5+, an angry fan throws a rock at that player. The player is immediately knocked down. </item>
        <item>Until the end of this half, any player on the opposing team that commits a foul action is automatically
        seen by the referee, even if a natural double is not rolled.</item>
        <item>Randomly select one player on your team that is available to play during this drive and that does not have
        the Loner (X+) trait. Until the end of the game, that player gains a single primary skill of your choice.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="nuffleNumber">1</string>
    <string name="nuffleHeader">Treacherous Trapdoor</string>
    <string name="nuffleDescription">Until the end of this half, every time any player enters a trapdoor square, for any reason, roll a D6. On a roll of 1,
        the trapdoor falls open and the player is immediately removed from play. Treat them exactly as if they had been pushed
        in the crowd. If the player was in possession of the ball, it bounces from the trapdoor square.</string>
</resources>